watchshopuk.com 2012-06-06

# Privacy Policy

Watch Shop operates a comprehensive policy for privacy and security. We aim to store the minimal amount of information possible to allow you to make purchases and offer you recommendations. 

We do not disclose, rent or lease any information submitted to us to 3rd parties for marketing purposes, except as stated in this policy. We do not use any of your data for any reason, except as stated in this policy, but to successfully ship your order to you. You have the option to sign up for an account in the checkout process. This means that your user data is stored on our servers. 

We may, sometimes, employ 3rd party companies for marketing purposes. In these cases, we may pass your name and email address on to a trusted 3rd party provider. Examples include sending e-mail newsletters, feedback requests and analysing data. The companies involved will not sell or lease your data, and will not market to you themselves. We make extensive efforts to ensure that any provider who receives your details operates a secure privacy policy so that your details will not be redistributed.

We store your name, address and telephone number if you register for an account with us.  This is optional, but enables you to place further orders without having to enter your details again. Your details are also stored in relation to unregistered orders.

We do not store your credit card information.  It is processed over a secure SSL/256 bit encryption system which goes through the payment provider Sagepay.  We do not handle or store this data, therefore it cannot be 'hacked' from our servers. Watch Shop staff do not have visibility of credit card numbers.

Optionally, you can supply us with a telephone number when ordering.  This is generally only used if we are unable to contact you via email.

If you wish, you can contact us to have your profile deleted at any point in time.

All sensitive information is processed over a secure servers.

We do not send marketing emails to random personal email address (spam), however from time to time we may send newsletters and special offers to registered customer email addresses. All of which include a facility for you to unsubscribe from such service by clicking on the link at the bottom of every newsletter sent. You can unsubscribe from our newsletter using this process anytime. To subscribe for the newsletter, you must opt in. Either in the checkout, or elsewhere on the site.

During the checkout process we may temporarily store your email address. This is not used for marketing purposes unless you opt into the newsletter. We may send you follow up email(s) if you do not complete the checkout process to remind you of the items in your cart for future reference and allow you to complete the purchase more easily.

All of our data collection and storage conforms to the requirements of the Data Protection Act, 1998. 

Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer by your browser when you visit web pages. We use cookies to allow us to store tracking information to make your user experience better. Cookie storage reasons include: Items in your shopping basket, usage statistics, and your favourite products. This information is not shared, and expires after a reasonable period of time. 

We collect and store data in cookies which is sent securely to remarketing companies, whose algorithms may determine if you will see advertising related to your browsing on other websites. You are able to opt out of these adverts at any time (more information below).

Cookies are necessary to purchase items at Watch Shop. They are used to identify items in your shopping bag, shortlist, and also your browsing history so we can make better recommendations. The cookies themselves do not store any personal identifiable information. Instead, they store a 'key' on your computer which then identifies information stored temporarily on our own server. You can disable cookies in your browser to prevent this, however you will not be able to use the primary functionality of this website. You can disable cookies in your browser's settings. If you are unsure how to do this, follow this link: [Disable browser cookies](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1). 

When placing an order, your email address will sent to a 3rd party feedback company called Feefo. Feefo may follow up your order with one email asking to give your feedback about your purchasing experience. Feefo won't spam you and won't pass your details onto any other party. You can read Feefo's full privacy policy at the following link: [Feefo's privacy policy](http://feefo.com/page/Privacy+Policy)

We use Google Analytics to track visitor numbers and behaviour. This service is to help us continually improve our service and does not track any personally identifiable information. If you wish to opt out of this, you should disable cookies in your browser. 

After visiting Watch Shop you may find advertising banners on other websites associated with your browsing history. The technology behind these services are based on cookies. This is a service offered to suggest alternate styles or items which may be of interest to you. This is an anonymous service and no personal or identifiable information is recorded by this advertising method, however if you do not wish to view these type of adverts you can opt out of these services at the following links:

To contact us about our privacy policy please use the Contact us button at the top of the website.
